医院夜惊魂
翻译
零九/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
那么，是时候隐藏起我的秘密身份了
Well, time to assume my secret identity.
此处康妮的秘密身份隐藏方式与超人类似
下周同一时间继续练习刀法吗？
Same time next week for sword training?
对啊，真可惜我不能在家继续练习
Yeah. It's a shame I can't practice more at home.
嘿，等下！
Hey, wait a sec. Hup!
可以吗？
May I?
敬上
Here-eth.
汝尽可使用吾母之刀
You can borrow-eth my mother's sword...Eth.
史蒂文，你真是太好了，不过语法有点问题啊
Steven, that's so nice, if grammatically incorrect.
但汝不可赠吾与汝母之刀
But thou can't just givest me thine mother's sword.
何不可？
Why not-eth?
皆因此刀之重要
Because it's really important-eth.
此乃汝需持有之因
That's exactly why you should have-eth it.
汝可在一周之内尽兴习刀
You can have all week to practice-eth with it-eth.
感谢
Pbbhhthank you.
我们得做好准备，如果我们要与孔雀石和橄榄石战斗的话
We got to be ready if we have to fight Malachite or Peridot
当然还有那些怪异的宝石融合实验体
or those creepy gem-fusion experiments.
我会确保这把刀不出差错的
I'll make sure nothing happens to it.
那是车库门的声音！我妈回家了！
That's the garage door. Mom's home.
我们必须得把刀藏起来
We have to hide the sword.
我妈不可能让我在家里放把刀的
There's no way mom would let me have this in the house.
狮子？狮子?
Lion? Lion?
他溜走了
He walked off.
我们该怎么办？
What are we gonna do?!
嗨，妈妈，我在完成六点钟的小提琴练习
Hi, mom. Just finishing my 6:00 violin practice.
你五分钟前就该完成了
You should have finished five minutes ago.
你早该开始七点钟的自习了
You're late for your 7:00 study hour.
你好，史蒂文
Hello, Steven.
嗨，莫雪伦医生
Hi, Dr. Maheshwaren.
你还好吧？
How are you?
坐着
Sitting!
今天工作并不轻松
I had a rough day at work,
我可不想碰到什么惊喜
and I'm not in the mood for any more surprises.
医院发生了什么事？
What happened at work?
今天遇到一件非常奇怪的事-
There was a really strange case at the hospital today --
如同噩梦一般
straight out of a nightmare.
哦，不过别担心
Oh, don't worry.
医患保密规则
The rules of doctor-patient confidentiality
不让我分享场面的细节，但-
keep me from sharing the graphic details, but --
等下，我们什么时候有了个大衣架？
hang on a moment. When did we get a coat rack?
哦，不
Oh, no.
一把刀？
A sword?!
康妮，你从哪里拿的？
Connie, where did you get this?!
这是-
It's --
我捡的！
I found it.
我无意间在外面发现的
I just found it outside,
而我想给史蒂文看看
and I wanted to show it to Steven.
你怎么能认为这是安全的？
How could you possibly think this is okay? It's --
你知道每天我在医院里见到多少孩子
do you know how many children I see every day in the hospital
因为玩刀而把自己脸切掉了？
who've cut their faces off playing with swords?
我-
I --
零！
none!
因为他们都有关爱他们的父母
Because they all have parents who love them
而父母们不会让孩子玩弄致命武器
and who don't let them play around with deadly weapons
搞得像混混一样！
like some kind of gang member!
不许摸刀-任何情况都不行！
No playing with swords under any circumstances.
我是莫雪伦医生，好的，冷静下，斯壮伯格
This is Dr. Maheshwaren. Yes, calm down, straumburg.
又有一个？
Another one?
她会还回刀吗？
Is she gonna give it back?
好吧，我-我马上就过去
All right, I'll -- I'll be right there.
我必须得去医院了
I have to go to the hospital.
我会和你爸商量
I'll have a talk with your father
算算你有多被禁足！
to calculate just how grounded you are.
而且我们要用算盘！
And we're using the abacus.
我讨厌那个算盘
I hate that abacus.
史蒂文，我太对不起了，她拿走了你母亲的刀
Steven, I'm so sorry. She took your mother's sword.
也许我们能让她回心转意？
Maybe we can get her to change her mind.
她从不改变想法
She never, ever changes her mind.
我们得靠自己拿回刀
We've got to get that sword back ourselves.
Whoa!
Ugh.
我们不能把狮子带进去
We can't bring Lion inside.
如果我妈把狮子也给没收了的话我会非常后悔的
I'd feel really bad if my mom confiscated him, too.
哦，这没什么，他可以呆在这里
Oh, it's no problem. He can stay out here.
听着，我总算找到了一个让他听从我的办法
Look -- I finally found a way to get him to do what I want.
都不撕掉塑料包装
He didn't even take the plastic off.
真是个禽兽啊
What an animal.
打住，要严肃
Okay, serious.
对，要严肃
Yeah. Serious.
这里
This way.
啊，你是指超级吓人的路
Ah, you mean the super scary way.
他们在晚餐后会将灯光调暗
They turn the lights down after dinner.
那是什么？
What was that?
维斯特医生可不会喜欢的
Dr. west ain't gonna like it.
Dr.West致敬1985年的邪典片《活跳尸》
不过，维斯特医生可不在这里
Well, Dr. west isn't here.
好的，好的，我刚到这里，嗯，嗯
Yes, yes, I just got here. Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
你再说一下在哪找到他们的？
Where did you say you found them?
路边？
The side of the road?
我现在还不确定，毕竟还没亲眼见过
I'm not sure just yet. I haven't had a look for myself.
这看起来可不像是车祸
It doesn't look like a car accident.
你没找到身份证件？
You didn't find an I.D.?
听着，我会回电话的，
Listen, I'll call you back
当，或者，我有问题的时候
when, or if, I have an answer for you.
再见
Goodbye.
好吧，现在
Okay, now.
她在做什么？
What's she doing?
她很可能在检查体征
She's probably checking their vitals.
你之前就没见过医院吗？
Haven't you been to a hospital before?
没
No.
哦，算你走运
Oh. Lucky.
史蒂文，看
Steven, look.
没有心跳
No heartbeat.
呃，便宜的医院报销货
Ugh. Cheap hospital budgets.
康妮！
Connie!
哦，不！
Oh, no!
你是怎么-你拿这个干嘛？！
How did you even -- what are you doing with this?!
我定了规矩-
I made a rule --
任何情况下都不能用刀
no swords under any circumstances.
但，母亲！
But, mom!
我们回家再说
We will finish this conversation at home.
先生？女士？维斯特先生？
Sir? Ma'am? Dr. west?
他一天都不休息，不是吗？
He can't take a day off, can he?
是你？这是我的另一位病人
You? It's my other patient.
你下床干什么
What are you doing out of bed?
为什么你没和斯壮伯格医生在一起？
Why aren't you with Dr. straumburg?
那不是病人
That's not a patient.
啊！
Aah!
我不知道这里发生了什么
I don't know what's going on here,
我会查个明白的
I am going to get to the bottom of it.
康妮，我觉得那是宝石变异体
Connie, I think that's one of the gem mutants.
什么？你确定？
What? Are you sure?
现在非常确定了
Pretty sure at this point.
母亲，我真的，真的，真的需要那把刀
Mom, I really, really, really need that sword.
康妮，不，现在不是合适的时候
Connie, no. Now is not the time.
就是现在，母亲！
Now is the perfect time, mom!
康妮，你这是怎么了？
Connie, what has gotten into you?
你知道我从不更改规矩的，小姑娘
You know I never go back on a rule, young lady.
总得有点例外吧？
There have to be some exceptions.
我又不是被规矩控制的机器人！
I'm not some rule-driven robot.
康妮！
Aah! Connie!
妈妈！
Mom!
我来救你了！
I'll save you!
过来！
Here!
把-你的-手-从我的康妮身上-拿开！
Keep your hands off my Connie!
这些患者真是不可理喻啊
These patients are beyond reason.
母亲，只要你这次愿意改变你的规矩...
Mom, if you would just go back on your rule this one time...
我只是需要帮助史蒂文并让我们逃离这里！
I just need to help Steven to get us out of here!
母亲最了解！
Mother knows best!
史蒂文，快！
Steven, come on!
哦，不！
Oh, no.
我们被困住了
We're trapped.
此处"Dr. Gero, Patient 20"致敬龙珠Z中的格罗博士（人造人20号）
我们不必如此
We don't have to be.
真的，妈妈，我知道该怎么做
Really, mom, I know how to do this.
不，你不知道
No, you don't.
不，她知道
Yes, she does.
她一直在练习
She's been training.
她不是在随意玩弄那把刀
She wasn't playing around with that sword.
她在上课，学习如何正确使用它
She was taking classes, learning how to use it right.
即使她一直在学习
Even though she's always studying
宝石实验体的设计参考了《死亡空间》中的怪物，而右下的那只则和求生之路2里的Charger相似
或者练习网球，或者做作业，
or practicing tennis or doing her homework,
她仍然在努力成为一名好的刀客
she still works really hard to be a good sword fighter.
不，不不不不不不
No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
我了解我女儿
I know my daughter.
我知道她每一天每一秒都在做什么-
I know what she's doing every second of the day --
她所有的活动，所有的网上交互
all her activities, all her internets.
我知道她不是某些玩刀的小混混！
I know she's definitely not some sword-fighting hooligan.
你一点都不了解我！
You don't know me at all!
你到现在还没注意到我的眼镜！
You still haven't even noticed my glasses.
你的眼镜有什么问题？
What's wrong with your glasses?
它都没有镜片了！
They don't have lenses anymore.
我都快一年用不到真正的眼镜了！
I haven't needed actual glasses for almost a year.
怎么？你的视力突然被魔法治好了？
What? Your eyesight just magically got better?
当然！
Yes!
我一直在与魔法和怪物打交道
I've been dealing with magic and monsters
康妮揭露秘密的情景和《野外怪家庭》类似——都是紧急关头不得不交代
还有这种东西，从我认识史蒂文开始
and things like these since I met Steven.
这也是为什么我需要你相信我知道该做什么
That's why I need you to believe I know what to do here.
但-你-
But you --
呃，现在没时间废话
ugh! There's no time for this.
准备好了？
Ready?
收起泡泡
Drop the bubble.
此处墙上的画源自游戏《看火人》的海报，而蓝色的松树则与《怪诞小镇》有关；
《怪诞小镇》的场景也为山林中的小镇，而主创Alex和Rebecca还是朋友
康妮用刀的招式与《剑风传奇》中的格斯类似
难怪它没有脉搏
So that's why it had no pulse.
宝石人实验品
Gem experiments.
这就是你一直在做的？
This is what you've been doing?
训练着与这些...东西战斗？
Training to fight these...Things?
啊～！
Aah!
对不起，莫雪伦医生
Sorry, Dr. Maheshwaren.
那是我的狮子
That's my Lion.
妈妈，我很抱歉我对你撒谎了
Mom, I'm really sorry about lying to you.
这一开始只是个小秘密
It started off as a tiny secret,
而我感觉如果我说出来
and then it felt like if I didn't hide it,
你不会再让我与史蒂文相处了
you wouldn't let me see Steven ever again.
这就是你的感受吗？我们是不是干预的太过了？
Is that how you feel? Are we too controlling?
也许吧
Maybe.
我只是想成为一个好母亲
I just wanted to be a good mother.
我-我只是想保护你
I-I just wanted to protect you.
我现在可以保护自己了
I can protect myself now.
好吧
Okay.
我们-会修改规矩的
We'll pull back on the rules,
而我会试着接受
and I'll try to keep an open mind
这个，那个，和...他
about this and that and...Him.
我很害怕我没法和你沟通
It scares me that you can't talk to me.
我得知道你的生活是什么样的
I need to know what's happening in your life.
我得在你 时
I need to step in when you're in over your head.
你能对我保证你停止遮掩吗？
Will you just promise me you'll stop all this lying?
那是个规矩
That's a rule.
我爱你，亲爱的
I love you, honey.
我也爱你，妈妈
I love you too, mom.
我认为我非常卑微
♪ I always thought I might be bad ♪
现在我已确定
♪ now I'm sure that it's true
因，你如此完美
♪ 'cause I think you're so good ♪
而我却丝毫不如
♪ and I'm nothing like you